Guide to the Irving Fisher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MICROFILM INVENTORY
  - Economic Essays, Vol. IX: "Stabilizing the Dollar", 1913 June 1 - 1919 January 1
    - General publications
      - Can the Purchasing Power of the Dollar be Controlled?, address at Reed College, Portland ( Evening Telegram, Portland), 1917 (Box 3)
        - Abstract from same ( Quest, Portland), 1917 (Box 3)
      - Abstract of address before Commercial Club of Seattle ( Times, Seattle), 1917 (Box 3)
      - Some Endorsements of a Plan for Standardizing the Dollar, 1918 (Box 3)
        - Second edition of same, 1918 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Dollar in Purchasing Power, preprint of chapter from "American Problems of Reconstruction", 1918 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same
          - Evening News, Buffalo, 1918 (Box 3)
          - The Post-Dispatch, St. Louis, Mo., 1918 (Box 3)
          - Ohio State Journal, Columbus, Ohio, 1918 (Box 3)
          - Post Intelligencer, Seattle, Wash., 1918 (Box 3)
          - Broadside sent out by Newspaper Enterprise Association, 1918 (Box 3)
          - Evening Record, Boston, 1918 (Box 3)
      - The Hole in the Dollar ( The Financier ), 1918 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of same ( Printers Ink, N.Y.C.), 1918 (Box 3)
    - Publications contained in other forms in previous volumes
      - Extract of Report before International Congress of Chambers of Commerce ( Market World and Chronicle ), 1912 (Box 3)
        See also: Vol. V, series 7, reel 2, volume 5
      - Extract from "A Compensated Dollar" ( City Club Bulletin ), 1913 (Box 3)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. X: "Stabilizing the Dollar", 1919 January 1 - 1922 January 1
    - General publications
      - Comment on A.C. Miller's address before Amer. Econ. Ass. ( Newark Evening News ), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Dollar (reprinted from Amer. Economic Review Supplement ), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of same (without cover), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of same ( Monthly Labor Review ), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1919 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same
          - Pioneer Press, St. Paul, Minn., 1919 (Box 3)
          - News, Raleigh, N.C., 1919 (Box 3)
          - Press, Phila., 1919 (Box 3)
          - "The Evolution of Money" by I. W. Sylvester, 1919 (Box 3)
        - Abstract from same ( Telegram, Elmira, N.Y.), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Abstract from same ( Evening Globe, N.Y.), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of same ( American Banker ), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Fourth Report of the "Committee on the Purchasing Power of Money in Relation to the War" of the Amer. Econ. Assoc. (broadside sent out by Newspaper Enterprise Assoc.), 1919 (Box 3)
        For Report 1, see: Vol. VII, series 7, reel 2, volume 7
        For Report 2, see: Vol. VII, series 7, reel 2, volume 7
        For Report 3, see: Vol VII, series 7, reel 2, volume 7
        - Reprint of first half of same ( Cleveland Press ), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of second half of same ( Cleveland Press ), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of same, complete ( Evening Sun, Baltimore), 1919 (Box 3)
      - "Peg" All Prices With Variable Gold Dollar Weight, extracts from Fourth Report ( N.Y. Commercial ), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Reprint of same ( Manufacturer's Record ), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before New York Business Publishers' Assoc. ( Jour. of Commerce, N.Y.C.), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same, ( Electric Railway Jour .), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before New England Assoc. of Purchasing Agents ( Herald, Boston), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same ( Transcript, Boston), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before Society of Polish Engineers and Merchants in Amer. ( Evening Post, N.Y.), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Dollar, address before Electrical Manufacturers' Club, Atlantic City (separate reprint), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Rejoinder to Dr. Knibbs' criticisms of plan ( American Economic Review ), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1919 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Dollar ( Youroveta Review ), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before Chamber of Commerce, Reading, Pa. ( Reading News ), 1919 (Box 3)
      - The Gamble in Gold ( The Magazine of Wall Street ), 1919 (Box 3)
      - High Prices; and a Remedy ( Review of Reviews ), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1919 (Box 3)
      - A Monetary Remedy for the High Cost of Living, address before 45th Annl. Convention, American Bankers Assoc., St. Louis (separate reprint), 1919 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from the same
          - Journal of the Amer. Bankers Assoc., 1919 (Box 3)
          - Michigan Manufacturer and Financial Record, 1919 (Box 3)
          - Finance and Industry, Cleveland, 1919 (Box 3)
          - The Economist, Chicago, 1919 (Box 3)
          - United States Investor, 1919 (Box 3)
          - Manufacturers' News, 1919 (Box 3)
      - From "Worth-While Thoughts from the A.B. Convention," compiled and presented by Mercantile Trust Co., St. Louis, Mo., 1919 (Box 3)
      - The Unruly Dollar ( Red Cross Magazine ), 1919 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address at Battle Creek Sanitarium ( Welfare Bulletin ), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before Rochester Chamber of Commerce ( Bulletin of the Chamber of Commerce ), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Dollar to Check H.C.L., syndicated by Washington Star, ( Star, Washington, D.C.), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Dollar ( The Federal Employee, Washington, D.C.), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Why Our Dollar Looks Like Thirty Cents ( Current Affairs, organ of Boston Chamber of Commerce), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Reply to criticism of Plan by Thomas York ( The Annalist ), 1920 (Box 3)
      - First Aid to the Dollar ( Leslie's Illustrated Weekly Newspaper ), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Dollar ( Annals of 12-L ), 1920 (Box 3)
      - The Stabilized Dollar ( Worcester Evening Gazette ), 1920 (Box 3)
      - A Discussion of Professor Cassel's Article ( Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science ), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Stabilising the Price Level ( Ways and Means, London, England), 1920 (Box 3)
      - Stabilizing the Price Level ( The Bank Officer, London, England), 1920 (Box 3)
      - A Dollar's Worth for a Dollar ( Business ), 1920 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1920 (Box 3)
      - How an Unstabilized Dollar Interferes with Efficient Management ( Bulletin of the Taylor Society ), 1921 (Box 3)
        - Extract from same ( Factory, Chicago), 1921 (Box 3)
      - The Present Chaos in Monetary Standards and How to Deal with It ( The Manufacturer, Philadelphia), 1921 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1921 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, revised edition, 1921 (Box 3)
        - Spanish translation of same ( Revista Economia Argentina, Buenos Aires), 1921 (Box 3)
      - Solution of H.C.L. Problem Lies in Stab. Dollar ( Civic Progress, Columbus, Ohio), 1921 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before Southern New England Chapter of Natl. Assoc. of Corporation Training ( Journal-Courier ), 1921 (Box 3)
      - Why Not Stabilize Our Dollar? ( The New England Purchaser ), 1921 (Box 3)
      - Address before organization mtg. of Stable Money League and reply to adverse report of the Amer. Bankers Assoc. ( Jour. of the American Bankers Assoc. ), 1921 (Box 3)
        - Separate reprint of same, 1921 (Box 3)
        - Extracts from same
          - Savings Bank Monthly Journal, N.Y., 1921 (Box 3)
          - The Northwestern Banker, 1921 (Box 3)
          - National Enquirer, Indianapolis, Ind., 1921 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from address before Unity Forum, Montclair, N.J. ( Montclair Times ), 1921 (Box 3)
      - Reply to editorial by W.I. Drummond ( Agricultural Review, Kansas City, Mo.), 1921 (Box 3)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XI: "Stabilizing the Dollar", 1922 - 1923
    - "Dollar Stabilization" ( Encyclopaedia Britannica, Vol. XXX, pp. 852-3), 1922 (Box 3)
    - "Business Depression" and "Instability of Money," two lectures given at London School of Economics ( Bankers Magazine, London), 1922 January (Box 3)
      - Same, in Norwegian ( Økonomisk Revue, Kristiana), 1922 February 1 (Box 3)
      - Same--2nd lecture ( Tribune, New York), 1921 December 11 (Box 3)
      - Full Employment--Prosperity's Problem (N.Y.C.), 1921 December 18 (Box 3)
    - 3rd in series of 5 articles, released by United Feature Syndicate ( Tribune, N.Y.), 1922 January 1 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same, Mfg. Asso. of Ct., 1922 May 25 (Box 3)
    - 4th in series of 5 articles, released by United Feature Syndicate ( Tribune, N.Y.), 1922 January 29 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same, Mfg. Asso. of Ct., 1922 May 29 (Box 3)
    - 5th in series of 5 articles, released by U. F. S. ( Tribune, N.Y.), 1922 February 12 (Box 3)
      - Same, in German ( Frankfurter Zeitung ), 1922 March 12 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same, Mfg. Asso. of Ct., 1922 June 3 (Box 3)
    - "Normal Price Level Illusory" ( Engineering News Record, N.Y., Vol. 88, No. 24), 1922 June 15 (Box 3)
    - "A Remarkable Analogy!," letter to, N.Y., Vol. V, No. 130, 1922 September 6 (Box 3)
    - Letter to Mr. Wanamaker ( Cotton News ), 1922 September 15 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before Southwestern Business Congress ( Tulsa Tribune ), 1922 October 19 (Box 3)
    - "Unstable Money & Prosperity," full account of address ( Tulsa Spirit ), 1922 November (Box 3)
    - "Stabilize Money or Face Fascisti Move in U.S." (Newspaper Enterprise Asso. Release), 1922 November 27 (Box 3)
      - Same ( Journal, Syracuse, N.Y.), 1922 November 28 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same ( Manufacturers Record ), 1923 January 4 (Box 3)
    - "Devaluation Versus Deflation" ( Manchester Guardian ), 1922 December 7 (Box 3)
    - Pamphlet reprint of article Manufacturers Record ), 1923 (Box 3)
    - "Stabilization of Europe" ( American Economic Review, Vol. XII, No. 1), 1923 March (Box 3)
    - German Trans. of "Theories Regarding the Value of Money" (before Academy of Polit. Science, Nov 1922) by. J. H. Buchi, Hamburg, 1925 (Box 3)
    - "Stabilizing the Dollar," Ch. II of "Stabilization of Business," edited by Lionel D. Edie, 1923 (Box 3)
      - Same, in German, Berlin, 1924 (Box 3)
    - "Stabilization of Purchasing Power of Money," statement at Hearing before Com. on Banking & Currency, H. of R., 67th Congress, 1922 (1923) December 18-21 (Box 3)
      - Same, Part II, Rebuttal, 1923 January 29 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from "Devaluation Versus Deflation," Manchester Guardian, ( Journal of Commerce, N.Y.), 1922 December 7 1923 January 27 (Box 3)
    - "Stabilizing the Dollar" ( International Molders' Journal, Cincinnati, Ohio), 1923 February (Box 3)
    - "Why I Expect a Boom in Business" ( Magazine of Wall Street, Vol. 31, No. 8), 1923 February 17 (Box 3)
    - Letter to Editor on Stable Money ( Post, Wash., D.C.), 1923 March 23 (Box 3)
      - Similar letter to Editor ( World, N.Y.), 1923 March 23 (Box 3)
      - Similar letter to Editor ( Star, Wash., D.C.), 1923 March 26 (Box 3)
      - Letter to Editor (same topic) ( Call, N.Y.), 1923 March 27 (Box 3)
    - Address as Witness before Committee on Banking and Currency, House of Commons, Canada, 1923 April 30 (Box 3)
      - Ditto, 1923 May 1 (Box 3)
      - Reprint of preceding two items together, 1923 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same ( Financial Times, Montreal), 1923 May 12 (Box 3)
    - "Who is Picking Your Pocket?," broadside of Newspaper Enterprise Asso., 1923 May 22 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before National Monetary Asso., Hotel Astor, N.Y., ( Times, N.Y.), 1923 June 71923 June 8 (Box 3)
      - Same, American, N.Y., 1923 June 8 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before Iowa Bankers Asso., Ames, Iowa ( Wallaces' Farmer, Des Moines), 1923 June 22 (Box 3)
    - "Money Prices of the World" ( Chicago Daily Journal, Midyear Financial Section), 1923 June 30 (Box 3)
    - "How to Take the Fidgets Out of Your Dollar" ( International Molders' Journal, Cin., O.), 1923 July (Box 3)
    - Reply to Fabian Franklin's criticism of Stable Dollar plan ( The Independent, N.Y.), 1923 July 21 (Box 3)
      - Reprint of same, 1923 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from testimony at Goldsborough Hearings, quoted in editorial, with reply ( Bankers Magazine ), 1923 August (Box 3)
    - Letter to Editor, re Keynes' plan for stabilizing price level using Bank of England rate ( Times, New York), 1923 September 2 (Box 3)
      - Reprint of same, 1923 (Box 3)
    - "The Dollar and the King's Waist-Line" ( American Review, Bloomington, Ill.), 1923 September - October (Box 3)
      - Reprint of same, 1923 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address on Stable Dollar before New Haven Woman's Club ( Yale News ), 1923 October 11 (Box 3)
      - Same ( Union, New Haven, Ct.), 1923 October 11 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address on Stable Dollar before Ohio Society of Certified Public Accountants, Cleveland, O., ( Times, Chester, Pa.), 1923 October 131923 October 24 (Box 3)
      - Same ( Leader, Cleveland, O.), 1923 October 14 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address (broadcast by W. G. Y.) before Schenectady Open Forum ( Gazette ), 1923 November 12 (Box 3)
    - Review of book by E. M. H. Lloyd, London, 1923 ( Post, New York), 1923 November 24 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before Adam Smith Club ( Wesleyan Argus, Middletown, Ct.), 1923 November 26 (Box 3)
    - "The Business Cycle, Largely a 'Dance of the Dollar'" ( American Statistical Asso. Journal ), 1923 December (Box 3)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XII: "Stabilizing Dollar", 1924 - 1926 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address on Stable Dollar, Freehold, N.J. ( Record, Long Branch, N.J.), 1924 January 31 (Box 3)
      - Same ( Transcript, Freehold, N.J.), 1924 (Box 3)
      - Same ( Monmouth Democrat, Freehold, N.J.), 1924 February 7 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address at Trenton Y.M.C.A. ( State Gazette, Trenton), 1924 February 1 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address at Mt. Holyoke College ( Republican, Springfield, Mass.), 1924 February 20 (Box 3)
    - Testimony before Committee on Banking & Currency of H. of R., 68th Congress, 1924 February 26 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same
        - Eagle, Brooklyn, N.Y., 1924 February 27 (Box 3)
        - Journal of Commerce, N.Y., 1924 February 27 (Box 3)
        - Sun, Baltimore, Md., 1924 February 27 (Box 3)
        - 2nd hearing Baltimore Sun, 1924 February 27 (Box 3)
        - N.Y. Commercial, N.Y., 1924 February 28 (Box 3)
    - "Stabilizing the Dollar" ( Harpers Mag. ), 1924 March (Box 3)
      - Reprint of same, 1924 (Box 3)
      - Trans. of same by Siegmund Speyerer, 1924 September (Box 3)
      - Reprint of German, trans. ( Deutsche Technische Warte, Erfurt), 1924 October 8 (Box 3)
      - Continuation of last item, 1924 October 15 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address on Stable Dollar before City Club, Chicago ( Journal of Commerce ), 1924 March 5 (Box 3)
      - Same ( Herald-Examiner, Chicago), 1924 March 5 (Box 3)
      - Same ( Pioneer Press, St. Paul, Minn.), 1924 March 30 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before Chamber of Commerce ( Register, Des Moines, Iowa), 1924 April 5 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before Ad Club, San Francisco, Cal. ( Chronicle ), 1924 July 24 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address, Babson Institute summer conference ( Eve. Transcript, Boston), 1924 August 15 (Box 3)
      - Same
        - Christian Science Monitor, Boston, 1924 August 15 (Box 3)
        - Herald, Boston, Mass., 1924 August 16 (Box 3)
        - Telegram, Worcester, Mass., 1924 August 16 (Box 3)
        - Interview re same, Christian Science Monitor, 1924 October 16 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from Babson address ( Chronicle, Halifax, Nova Scotia), 1924 August 30 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before Amer. Statistical Society ( Journal of Commerce, N.Y.C.), 1924 November 8 (Box 3)
      - Same
        - Commercial, N.Y.C., 1924 November 8 (Box 3)
        - Herald-Tribune, N.Y.C., 1924 November 9 (Box 3)
        - Daily Colonist, Victoria, B.C., 1924 November 16 (Box 3)
        - The Glass Industry, 1925 January (Box 3)
    - Interview re "Goods Dollar" ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1924 December 17 (Box 3)
    - Statement prepared for Engineering News-Record ( Public Ledger, Phila., Pa.), 1925 January 1 (Box 3)
    - Address before Boston Ethical Society on "Ethics in the Monetary System" ( Christian Work, New York), 1925 January 10 (Box 3)
      - Part II of same, 1925 January 17 (Box 3)
      - Part III of same, 1925 January 24 (Box 3)
      - Reprint of all three parts of same, pamphlet, 1925 (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same ( The Standard, N.Y.), 1925 January (Box 3)
      - Spanish trans. of same ( Inter-America, N.Y.), 1925 July (Box 3)
      - Spanish trans. of same, reprinted ( Revistade Economia Argentina, Buenos Aires), 1925 October (Box 3)
      - German trans. of same, Bern, 1925 (Box 3)
    - "Our Now Unstable Dollar Hurts All of Us," released by Associated Editors, Inc., 1925 February 15 (Box 3)
      - Reprint of same ( Post, Wash., D.C.), 1925 February 15 (Box 3)
    - "Takes Issue with I.F. on Dollar," letter to the Editor by W. W. Baldwin ( News, Chicago), 1925 February 19 (Box 3)
    - Tribute to Walter Camp ( Herald-Tribune, N.Y.C.), 1925 March 15 (Box 3)
    - Quotes re Dollar in remarks by Charles I. Stengle ( Congressional Record, Wash., D.C.), 1925 February 26 (Box 3)
    - Reply to letter of W. W. Baldwin (above) ( Post, Wash., D.C.), 1925 March 15 (Box 3)
    - "The Future of the Gold Standard," in John Parke Young's report to Commission on Gold & Silver Inquiry, U.S. Senate, Wash., D.C., 1925 March (Box 3)
    - "Has the Time Come for an International Currency Conference?" ( Baltic-Scandinavian Trade Review and Mirror of World Commerce, Copenhagen), 1925 March 11 (Box 3)
    - "Our Unstable Dollar and the So-called Business Cycle" ( Journal of Amer. Statistical Asso. ), 1925 June (Box 3)
      - Simplified version of same ( Kardex Service ), 1925 September (Box 3)
      - Extracts from same ( New York Journal ), 1925 November 15 (Box 3)
    - "Price Level Decline Far Off," for Economists' Forum, syndicated by Asso. Editors ( Post, Wash., D.C.), 1925 August 16 (Box 3)
    - "Steady Prices Ahead" ( Journal, Chi., Ill.), 1925 December 31 (Box 3)
    - Statement re business conditions ( Purchaser, N.Y.C.), 1926 January (Box 3)
    - "Stable Price Level Assures Prosperity" ( Express, San Antonio, Texas), 1926 January 1 (Box 3)
    - "Dollar is Merely 62-Cent Piece" (on 1913 basis) ( Gazette, Worcester, Mass.), 1926 January 5 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from Chamber of Commerce address ( Morning Call, Paterson, N.J.), 1926 February 17 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address, Illinois Farmers' Institute ( Whig-Journal, Quincy, Ill.), 1926 February 24 (Box 3)
    - Interview re farmer's problem en route to Qunicy, Ill. ( Tribune, Chicago, Ill.), 1926 February 26 (Box 3)
    - Full report of Quincy address, pamphlet issued by Illinois Farmers' Institute, 1926 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from testimony before House Committee on Banking & Currency ( U.S. Daily, Wash.), 1926 March 26 (Box 3)
    - Letter to Editor re Control of Price Level ( News, Chicago, Ill.), 1926 June 18 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address at summer session (Battle Creek College ( Moon-Journal, Battle Creek), 1926 July 17 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address, Amer. Grocery Specialty. Mfgs' Asso. Convention ( Bulletin, Prov., R.I.), 1926 October 6 (Box 3)
    - Extracts from address before Bankers & B. Clerks' Mutual-Benefit Asso. ( Ledger, Phila., Pa.), 1926 November 16 (Box 3)
      - Same
        - Star, Indianapolis, Ind., 1926 November 16 (Box 3)
        - Bankers Magazine, N.Y.C., 1926 December (Box 3)
        - Amer. Bankers Asso. Journal, 1926 December (Box 3)
        - Service Bulletin, Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland, O., 1926 December 1 (Box 3)
        - Full address, pamphlet reprint from Money and Commerce, Pa. & W. Va. Bankers. Asso. & Penn. Title Asso., 1926 December 11 (Box 3)
        - Extracts, Boies Business Bulletin Service, Bloomfield, N.J., 1926 December 15 (Box 3)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XIII: "Stabilizing the Dollar", 1927 - 1931
    - "Stable Money," extracts from address before Bankers and Bank Clerks' Mutual Benefit Asso., ( The National Merchant and Manufacturer, Nashville, Tenn.), 1926 November 151927 January (Box 4)
      See also: Vol. XII, series 7, reel 3, volume 12
    - Extracts from "Banking Policy and Unemployment" ( Journal, New Haven, Ct.), 1926 January 9 (Box 4)
    - Condensation of 1st item above ( The Spur ), 1927 January 15 (Box 4)
    - "The Present State of Stabilization" ( The Manufacturer, Phila., Pa.), 1927 February (Box 4)
    - Extracts from address before Conn. Branch, Nat'1 Fed. of P.O. Clerks, New Haven, 1927 February 23 (Box 4)
    - Extracts from address, 37th Convention Missouri Bankers Asso. ( News Herald, Joplin, Mo.), 1927 May 17 (Box 4)
      - Same ( Financial Age, N.Y.C.), 1927 May 28 (Box 4)
      - Same ( The Bank Director, N.Y.C.), 1927 June (Box 4)
    - Extracts from address before Convention of Kansas Bankers Asso., Manhattan, Kan. ( The Kansas Industrialist, Manhattan, Kan.), 1927 May 25 (Box 4)
      - Same
        - Journal, Salina, Kan., 1927 May 19 (Box 4)
        - Journal, Topeka, Kan., 1927 May 19 (Box 4)
        - Times, Kansas City, Mo., 1927 May 20 (Box 4)
        - Chronicle, Manhattan, Kan., 1927 May 20 (Box 4)
    - Same ( News, Denver, Colo.), 1927 May 21 (Box 4)
    - Extracts from address before City Club, Kansas City, Mo., ( Journal, Kansas City, Mo.), 1927 May 20 (Box 4)
    - Extracts from address before 32nd Convention of Nat'1 Asso. of Credit Men (auspices Robert Morris Associates), Louisville, Ky., ( News Record, N.Y.C.), 1927 June 71927 June 8 (Box 4)
      See also: Vol. XV, series 7, reel 4, volume 15
      - Same ( Journal-Courier, Louisville, Ky.), 1927 June 8 (Box 4)
    - Release for 1st of 3 lectures on "Money Illusion," School of International Studies, Geneva, Switz. ( Financial Times, London, Eng.), 1927 August 31 (Box 4)
      - Same
        - Journal, Nottingham, Eng., 1927 August 30 (Box 4)
        - N.Y. Herald, Paris, France, 1927 August 31 (Box 4)
        - Chicago Tribune, Paris, 1927 August 30 (Box 4)
        - Dutch trans. Telegraaf, Amsterdam, 1927 September 1 (Box 4)
        - Financial News, London, 1927 August 31 (Box 4)
    - Release for 2nd of 3 lectures on "Money Illusion" at Geneva ( Financial Times, London), 1927 September 1 (Box 4)
      - Extracts from same ( Financial Times ), 1927 September 1 (Box 4)
      - Same
        - Chicago Tribune, Paris, 1927 August 31 (Box 4)
        - N.Y. Herald, Paris, 1927 September 1 (Box 4)
        - Nottingham Journal, Eng., 1927 August 31 (Box 4)
        - German trans. Weser Zeitung, Bremen, Germany, 1927 September 2 (Box 4)
        - Cape Times, Cape Town, South Africa, 1927 September 27 (Box 4)
    - Abstract from address, Convention of International Asso. for Social Progress, Vienna ( N.Y. Herald, Paris, France), 1927 September 21 (Box 4)
    - Release for 3rd Geneva lecture ( Journal, Nottingham, Eng.), 1927 September 1 (Box 4)
      - Same ( Financial News, London), 1927 September 2 (Box 4)
      - Extracts from same ( Financial Times ), 1927 September 2 (Box 4)
      - Same
        - N.Y. Herald, Paris, 1927 September 2 (Box 4)
        - Chicago Tribune, Paris, 1927 September 1 (Box 4)
        - German trans. Weser Zeitung, Bremen, 1927 September 2 (Box 4)
        - Pester Lloyd Morganblatt, Budapest, 1927 September 4 (Box 4)
      - Quote from same in letter to editor by T. B. Johnston ( Times & Mirror, Bristol, Eng.), 1927 September 11 (Box 4)
    - Statement made, arriving New York on "Homeric" ( Journal, Syracuse, N.Y.), 1927 September 29 (Box 4)